samantha craig

Product Design Engineer

profile

I'm a Product Design Engineer, specializing in digital product development and user-centered design. I use both art and science to develop user-focused products, and I love turning creative ideas into a reality.

Outside of the office, you can find me covered in paint and listening to a podcast while I repurpose something I found at a thrift store.

- samantha-craig.com
- samantha.sdc@icloud.com
- 916.865.6888

skills

Software

Adobe Creative Cloud, GitHub, Sketch, SolidWorks, SketchUp, Unity, Balsamiq, Axure, G Suite

Technical

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Linux, Git, Web Hosting, 3D Printing, Wireframing, SaaS, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality

Other

Agile, Project Management, Prototyping, User Testing, Testing & QA, Technical Writing, Market Analysis, Use Cases, Information Architecture, Interdisciplinary Communication

education

B.S. Interdisciplinary Engineering

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo | 2019 Concentrations - Product Engineering, Web Design & Development

experience

Product & Process Designer

GROW Design & Development | June 2019 - Present

- Created product documentation for web-based software
- · Defined development, testing, and deployment plans for software releases
- Wrote project case studies, white papers, and website content
- · Designed product marketing materials
- · Performed software testing & QA

Product Designer

Renovisions Independent Project | January 2019 - Present

- Developed product concept for home renovation-focused CAD software
- · Conducted interviews with customers and industry professionals
- Designed and tested user interface using mockups and wireframes
- · Defined product engineering requirements, use cases, workflows, and specs

Student Innovation Programs Coordinator

Cal Poly Center for Innovation & Entrepreneurship | April 2018 - June 2019

- Managed schedule of workshops, roundtables, pitches, and visiting executives
- Organized applications, interviews, team selection, and member management
- Coached companies on pitch presentation design, content, and delivery
- · Coordinated and supervised community service events

Virtual Reality & Augmented Reality Design Lead

LAES Passageway Project | April 2018 - December 2018

- Developed Unity virtual reality model for Sacramento K-Street tunnel renovation
- Completed project using Agile sprints for interdisciplinary team collaboration
- Specialized in visual texture design for VR modeling team
- Led UI/UX team to design augmented reality mobile application prototype
- Managed versioning and merging on GitHub for dozens of team members

Freelance Designer

Various Projects | 2015 - Present

- Performed user experience research and design
- Conducted user testing with mockups, wireframes, prototypes, & final products
- · Redesigned branding and websites for established companies
- Created information architecture plans for new websites and software
- Collaborated with back-end and front-end developers to build web platforms
- Designed and developed websites with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript